Inventory of the Iris Chang papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Biographical file
  - Miscellany, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 131: 5)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Birthday and holiday cards, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 131: 6-7)
  - General, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 131: 8)
  - General (Box 132)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 132: 1)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 132: 2)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 132: 3)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 132: 4)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 132: 5)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 132: 6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 132: 7)
  - Relatives, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 132: 8)
  - Orfield, Amy, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 132: 9)
  - Szohe, Kathy, undated (Box-folder 132: 10)
  - Kröger, Peter, and family, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 132: 11)
    Includes a photocopied diary excerpt by Christian Kröger relating to the Rape of Nanking, 1938.
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Notebooks, undated (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - School papers, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 133: 2-3)
  - Articles and stories written as course assignments, circa 1987 (Box-folder 133: 3-6)
    Includes some writings by others.
  - Childhood stories and poems, 1970s (Box-folder 134: 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous stories, 1970s (Box-folder 134: 5)
  - High school writing assignments, 1983 (Box-folder 134: 6)
- Biographical file
  - Artworks, 1970s (Box-folder 134: 7)
  - Coin collection, 1970s (Box-folder 134: 8)
    Includes notebook itemizing collection.
  - Student records (Box 135)
    - High school, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 135: 1-3)
    - University, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 135: 4)
  - Student publications
    - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 135: 5-6)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 135: 7)
    - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 136: 1)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 136: 2-3)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 136: 4)
    - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 136: 5)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 136: 6-10)
  - University High School, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 136: 11)
  - American Indians, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 136: 12)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 1)
  - Job search, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 2-3)
  - Graduate Record Examination, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 4)
  - Asian American Journalists Association, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 137: 5)
  - American Society of Magazine Editors, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 137: 6)
  - Writing clubs, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 137: 7)
  - Associated Press, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 8)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 137: 9-10)
  - Baltimore Sun, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 137: 11)
  - Gannett, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 12)
  - New York Times, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 137: 13)
  - Miami Herald, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 137: 14)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 15)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 16)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 137: 17)
  - Smithsonian, undated (Box-folder 137: 18)
  - Science, 1989 (Box-folder 137: 19)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 137: 20)
  - Washington Post, 1990 (Box-folder 137: 21)
  - 'Teen and Seventeen, 1991 (Box-folder 137: 22)
  - National Geographic, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 137: 23)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 137: 24)
  - Rent, 1990 (Box-folder 137: 25)
  - Financial aid, 1990 (Box-folder 137: 26)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1991 (Box-folder 138: 1)
    Includes some writings by Iris Chang.
  - Tajima, Renee, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 138: 2)
  - Chinese immigration, United States and Canada, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 138: 3)
    Includes article by Iris Chang.
  - Horton, Thomas, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 138: 4)
  - Education of gifted children, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 138: 5)
  - General, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 138: 6-8)
- Biographical file
  - Diplomas, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 139: 1-2)
  - Mensa Society correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 139: 3)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 139: 4)
  - Medals and ribbons, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 138: 5)
  - Awards and certificates, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 138: 6)
  - Résumés, 1989 (Box-folder 138: 7)
  - Clippings, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 138: 8)
  - Student publications, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 139: 9)
- Speeches and writings by others, 1989 (Box-folder 139: 10)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Newspaper articles
    - Associated Press, 1989 (Box-folder 139: 11)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 140: 1-8)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 140: 9-61)
  - Date books containing appointments and diary entries, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 141: 1-2)
  - Notes, undated (Box-folder 141: 3)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - General, 2000 (Box-folder 141: 4)
  - Committee of 100
    - 2000 (Box-folder 141: 5-7)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 142: 1-2)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 142: 3-4)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 142: 5-8)
- Videorecordings relating to the People's Republic of China, undated
  - 12 VHS videocassettes (Box-folder 143: 1-12)
  - 13 VHS videocassettes (Box-folder 144: 1-13)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Typescript, 2001 (Box-folder 145: 1-6)
    - Correspondence with editor Caroline White, 2001 (Box-folder 146: 1)
    - Master outline, 2000 (Box-folder 146: 2)
      Includes suggestions by Sara Lippincott.
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 146: 3-7)
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box 147)
    - Advance notice of publication, 1995 (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - Media coverage, undated (Box-folder 147: 2)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Reviews, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 147: 3-7)
    - Scrapbook with photographs depicting Iris Chang's promotional appearances in Houston, Texas, 1998 February 5-7 (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Articles on writing of book, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 149: 1-23)
    - Press kit, 1998 (Box-folder 150: 1)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Clipping relating to author appearances, 2003 (Box-folder 150: 2)
    - Reviews, 2003 (Box-folder 150: 3-6)
  - "Fear of SARS, Fear of Strangers," New York Times, 2003 May 21 (Box-folder 150: 7-8)
  - "Betrayed by the White House," New York Times, 2001 December 24 (Box-folder 151: 1)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Reviews, 2003 (Box-folder 151: 2-3)
    - Author appearances, 2003 (Box-folder 151: 4)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 151: 5-8)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 152: 1-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 153: 1-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 154: 1-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 155: 1-6)
  - Thread of the Silkworm. Reviews, 1996 (Box-folder 156: 1)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 156: 2-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 157: 1-5)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 157: 6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 158: 1-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 159: 1-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 160: 1-6)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, reviews and features on appearances by Iris Chang, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 161: 1-2)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 161: 3-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 162: 1-6)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 163: 1)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 163: 2-6)
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 164: 1-4)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, reviews, 2003 (Box-folder 164: 5)
- Biographical file
  - Clipping and serial issue, 2000 (Box-folder 164: 6)
  - Coloring book featuring Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 164: 7)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Committee of 100, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 164: 8)
  - General, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 164: 9)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Articles in Chicago Tribune, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 165: 1)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, reviews and features on Iris Chang, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 165: 2)
  - Thread of the Silkworm, reviews and features on Iris Chang, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 165: 3-6)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, reviews and features on Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 166: 1-4)
- Biographical file, clippings, 2004 (Box-folder 166: 5-6)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Reviews and features on Iris Chang, 2003 (Box-folder 167: 1)
    - Book tour, 2003 (Box-folder 167: 2)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II, reviews and features on Iris Chang or the Nanking Massacre, 1997 (Box-folder 167: 3)
- Biographical file
  - Family photographs, 1944-2004 (Box-folder 167: 4)
  - Clipping, undated (Box-folder 167: 5)
  - Coloring book featuring Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 167: 6)
  - Directory with biographical entry for Iris Chang, 2003 (Box-folder 167: 7)
  - Northern California Book Award, 2004 (Box-folder 167: 8)
  - Memorabilia, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 167: 9-10)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - General, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 168: 1)
  - Asian Business League of San Francisco, 2003 (Box-folder 168: 2)
- Photograph, one print depicting the remains of Nanking Massacre victims, 1946 (Box-folder 168: 3)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Book ideas and proposals
    - Diving book
      - Research materials, 1969-1995 (Box-folder 168: 4-9)
        Includes photocopies.
      - Research materials, 1969-1995 (Box-folder 169: 1)
      - Correspondence, interview transcript, and notes, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 169: 2)
      - Sound recordings, 1994 (Box-folder 169: 3-5)
        Three compact sound cassettes
    - "Turning Back the Biological Clock: The Fertility Revolution that Is Redefining Power between Men and Women"
      - Monographs, 1996 (Box-folder 169: 6)
      - Sound recording, 1996 (Box-folder 169: 7)
      - Research materials, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 169: 8)
      - Research materials, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 170: 1-6)
  - New York Times articles
    - "Fear of SARS, Fear of Strangers,", 2003 May 21 (Box-folder 170: 7)
      Correspondence, research materials, and typescript drafts.
    - Unpublished editorial, 2004 (Box-folder 170: 8)
      Typescript and correspondence.
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box 171)
    - Typescript drafts, 2001 (Box-folder 171: 1-6)
    - Correspondence with editor, 2001 (Box-folder 171: 7)
- Writings by others
  - Maga, Tim (Box-folder 172: 1-2)
    Includes comments by Iris Chang.
  - Bix, Herbert, 2000 (Box-folder 172: 3-5)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Japanese war atrocities, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 172: 6)
  - Newsweek, 2003 (Box-folder 172: 7)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - General research, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 173: 1-4)
  - Book ideas and proposals
    - Detoxify your home and life, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 173: 5)
    - K-9 corps, 2001 (Box-folder 173: 6)
    - Coast Guard history, 2001 (Box-folder 173: 7)
    - Mommy tax, 2001 (Box-folder 173: 8)
    - Women entrepreneurs, 2001 (Box-folder 173: 9)
    - Inspirational stories, 2000 (Box-folder 173: 10)
    - Billionaire women, 2000 (Box-folder 173: 11)
    - Spies on skis, 1995 (Box-folder 173: 12)
    - Sun Tzu for women, 1999 (Box-folder 173: 13)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Birth announcement for Christopher Joseph Chang Douglas, 2002 (Box-folder 174: 1)
  - General, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 174: 2-6)
  - General, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 175: 1)
  - Letters of condolence received by the family of Iris Chang, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 175: 2-4)
- Biographical file
  - "Remembering Iris Chang 1968-2004," memorial pamphlet, University of Illinois, undated (Box-folder 175: 5)
  - Memorial resolutions in honor of Iris Chang
    - California State Assembly, 2005 January 6 (Box-folder 175: 6)
    - Chicago City Council, 2004 December 18 (Box-folder 175: 7)
  - Obituaries, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 175: 8)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Iris Chang Journalism Award Fund, University of Illinois Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 176: 1)
  - Letters of condolence received by the family of Iris Chang, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 176: 2-6)
  - Letters of condolence received by the family of Iris Chang, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 177: 1-2)
  - Reading lists, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 177: 3-4)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 177: 5)
  - Soros fellowship, 2003 (Box-folder 177: 6)
- Biographical file
  - Tribute, House of Representatives, 2004 November 17 (Box-folder 178: 1)
  - Children's artworks commemorating Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 178: 2)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Letters of condolence received by the family of Iris Chang, 2004 (Box-folder 178: 3)
  - Writers' retreats, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 178: 4)
  - Lamarr, Hedy, 1995 (Box-folder 178: 5)
  - General
    - 2004 (Box-folder 178: 6)
    - 1998
      - January (Box-folder 178: 7)
      - February (Box-folder 178: 8)
      - March (Box-folder 179: 1)
      - April (Box-folder 179: 2)
      - May (Box-folder 179: 3)
      - June (Box-folder 179: 4)
      - July (Box-folder 179: 5)
      - August (Box-folder 179: 6)
      - September (Box-folder 179: 7)
      - October (Box-folder 179: 8)
      - November (Box-folder 180: 1)
      - December (Box-folder 180: 2)
    - 1999
      - January (Box-folder 180: 3)
      - February (Box-folder 180: 4)
      - March (Box-folder 180: 5)
      - April (Box-folder 180: 6)
      - May (Box-folder 180: 7)
      - June (Box-folder 180: 8)
      - July (Box-folder 181: 1)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang, notebooks relating to research on book topics and other projects
  Includes some personal writings.
  - 1998-2001 (Box-folder 181: 2-22)
  - 1999 (Box-folder 182: 1-22)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - IDI Corporation, undated (Box-folder 183: 1)
  - Fripp, Patricia, 2001 (Box-folder 183: 2)
  - Home decoration, 1996-2003 (Box-folder 183: 3-5)
  - General
    - 1997
      - November (Box-folder 183: 6)
      - December (Box-folder 183: 7)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 183: 8)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang, notebooks largely relating to newspaper articles written by Iris Chang
  - Undated (Box-folder 184: 1-20)
  - Undated (Box-folder 185: 1-21)
  - 1988 (Box-folder 185: 22)
  - Undated (Box-folder 186: 1-20)
  - Undated (Box-folder 187: 1-20)
  - Undated (Box-folder 188: 1-20)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Public health grants, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 189: 1)
  - Journalism grants, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 189: 2)
  - National Science Foundation grant, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 189: 3-7)
  - Aerospace history grants, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 190: 1)
  - Rejections and ineligible grants, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 190: 2)
  - Wilbur grant, 1995 (Box-folder 190: 3)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center fellowship, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 190: 4)
  - Peace grants, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 190: 5-6)
  - Pope Foundation awards, 1995 (Box-folder 190: 7)
  - Chinese grants, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 191: 1-3)
  - Mark Victor Hansen programs, 2002 (Box-folder 191: 4-6)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1990-1999 (Box-folder 192: 1)
  - Fulbright Scholar Program, 1996 (Box-folder 192: 2)
  - Corporate grants, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 192: 3-6)
  - Grant possibilities, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 193: 1)
  - National Federation of Press Women, 1991 (Box-folder 193: 2)
  - Gannett Foundation Journalism Scholarship, 1991 (Box-folder 193: 3)
  - Scripps Howard Foundation, 1998 (Box-folder 193: 4)
  - Scholarships and fellowships, 1990 (Box-folder 193: 5)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Story ideas and press releases, 1990 (Box-folder 193: 6)
  - Notebooks containing personal writings
    - Undated (Box-folder 193: 7)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 193: 8-16)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 193: 17)
  - Note cards containing personal writings, undated (Box-folder 194: 1-10)
  - Note cards containing personal writings, undated (Box-folder 195: 1-10)
  - Notebooks containing personal writings (Box 196)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 196: 1-7)
    - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 196: 8)
  - Ideas for writing and marketing
    - Travel writing, 1991 (Box-folder 196: 9)
    - Product ideas, 2002 (Box-folder 196: 10)
    - Self-publishing, 2003 (Box-folder 196: 11)
    - Direct mail, 2002 (Box-folder 196: 12)
    - Sex and fertility, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 196: 13)
    - Exceptional women, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 196: 14)
    - Unusual people, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 196: 15)
    - Childcare, 2003 (Box-folder 196: 16)
    - Interracial marriage, 1969-1997 (Box-folder 197: 1-5)
    - Baby IQ, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 197: 6-7)
    - Scars of steel, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 198: 1)
- Educational and motivational courses
  - Notes taken by Iris Chang, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 198: 2-10)
  - Sound recordings
    - "Great Screenwriting" by John Truby, 1985 (Box-folder 198: 11-22)
      12 compact sound cassettes
    - "Myth" by John Truby, 1991 (Box-folder 199: 1-4)
      4 compact sound cassettes
    - "Horror, Fantasy, and SciFi" by John Truby, 1998 (Box-folder 199: 5-8)
    - "Advanced Screenwriting" by John Truby, 1998 (Box-folder 199: 9-12)
  - Printed matter relating to screenwriting, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 199: 13)
  - Printed matter relating to screenwriting, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 200: 1-6)
  - Certificate and diploma awarded to Iris Chang, 2001 (Box-folder 200: 7)
- Biographical file
  - "The Woman Who Wouldn't Forget," Reader's Digest, 1998 September (Box-folder 201: 1-20)
    Biographical article published in English and in foreign translation in various international editions of this periodical.
  - Publicity materials, undated (Box-folder 202: 1)
  - Notecards depicting University High School, Urbana, Illinois, 1996 (Box-folder 202: 2)
  - Notecards reproducing a painting of Iris Chang by Glenn Zucman, 2000 (Box-folder 202: 3-10)
  - Speeches and writings by Iris Chang (Box 203)
  - "The Poetry of Science," master's thesis, Johns Hopkins University, 1991 (Box-folder 203: 1)
  - "The Aquarium" and "The Tornado," short stories, 1991 (Box-folder 203: 2)
  - Book ideas
    - General, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 203: 3)
    - Telephone psychics, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 203: 4)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation
    - 1999 (Box-folder 203: 5)
    - 1992-1995 (Box-folder 204: 1-3)
  - Grant proposals, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 204: 4)
  - Ford, Anitra, 1993 (Box-folder 204: 5)
  - Parkland College, 1990 (Box-folder 204: 6)
  - Wedding cards, 1991 (Box-folder 205: 1-2)
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 205: 3-5)
- Materials relating to Iris Chang's tenure as an instructor, Johns Hopkins University
  - Course reader, 1990 (Box-folder 205: 5)
  - Syllabus, 1990 (Box-folder 205: 6)
  - Student papers, 1990 (Box-folder 205: 7-8)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang, 1995 (Box-folder 206: 1-7)
  Typescript drafts of Thread of the Silkworm, including correspondence.
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Wedding cards, 1991 (Box-folder 207: 1-4)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 207: 5)
- Biographical file
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box-folder 207: 6)
  - Marriage certificate, 1991 (Box-folder 207: 7)
- Academic career file
  - Johns Hopkins University
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 207: 8)
    - Transcripts, 1990 (Box-folder 207: 9)
    - Master's thesis, 1991 (Box-folder 208: 1)
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign
    Course work, term papers, and printed matter.
    - 1985 (Box-folder 208: 2)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 208: 3)
    - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 208: 4-5)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 209: 1-2)
    - 1988-1990 (Box-folder 209: 3)
  - University High School, Urbana, Illinois
    - 1983 (Box-folder 209: 4)
    - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 209: 5-6)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 210: 1)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 210: 2-6)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 210: 7)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 211: 1)
- Materials relating to Iris Chang's tenure as an instructor, Johns Hopkins University
  - Syllabus and lecture notes, 1991 (Box-folder 211: 2-3)
  - Student papers, 1991 (Box-folder 211: 4-5)
  - Class record book, undated (Box-folder 211: 6)
  - Syllabus and lecture notes, 1990 (Box-folder 212: 1)
- Academic career file. John Hopkins University, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 212: 2-6)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - "Breaking News," play, 1990 (Box-folder 213: 1-2)
  - Notebooks relating to research and writing projects
    - Undated (Box-folder 213: 3-10)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 214: 1-26)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 215: 1)
    - Undated (Box-folder 215: 2)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 215: 3-8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 216: 1-5)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 216: 6-9)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 216: 10-18)
    - Undated (Box-folder 217: 1-16)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 217: 17-20)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 217: 21)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 218: 1-17)
    - Undated (Box-folder 218: 18)
    - Undated (Box-folder 219: 1-8)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 219: 9-14)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 219: 15-18)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 219: 19-23)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 219: 24)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 220: 1-14)
    - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 220: 15)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 220: 16-25)
- Telephone message books, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 221: 1-3)
- Academic career file, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign
  Correspondence and printed matter.
  - Phi Beta Chi, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 221: 4)
  - Homecoming, 1988 (Box-folder 221: 5)
  - Golden Key National Honor Society, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 221: 6)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 221: 7)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Job leads, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 221: 8)
  - Freelancing, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 221: 9)
  - Newsweek, 1988 (Box-folder 222: 1)
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1989 (Box-folder 222: 2)
  - University of Chicago, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 222: 3)
  - Graduate schools, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 222: 4)
  - Wa-Na-See, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 222: 5)
  - Society of Professional Journalists, 1989 (Box-folder 222: 6)
  - Scholarships, 1989 (Box-folder 222: 7)
  - Résumés, 1989 (Box-folder 222: 8)
  - Seventeen, 1988 (Box-folder 222: 9)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - General, 1989 (Box-folder 223: 1)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles
    - Daily Illini, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 223: 2-3)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1988 (Box-folder 223: 4)
    - Illinois Technograph, 1988 (Box-folder 223: 5)
    - Campus Voice, 1988 (Box-folder 223: 6)
    - New York Times, 1989 (Box-folder 223: 7)
- Academic career file
  Course work, papers, and printed matter.
  - University High School, Urbana, Illinois
    - Undated (Box-folder 224: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 224: 2-6)
  - University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1988 (Box-folder 225: 1)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Cornell University, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 225: 2-3)
  - University of Chicago, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 225: 4-5)
  - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 225: 6)
- Biographical file
  - Award plaque, undated (Box-folder 226: 1)